# Ryan Muller

Contact

2606 Humboldt Ave S, Unit 7 Minneapolis, MN 55408 ryan@learnstream.org http://ryanmuller.me

#### **OBJECTIVE**

# To create software that empowers people to discover, learn, and manage knowledge.

I understand effective learning and have worked with data and people to bring educational content to interactive web interfaces. I would like to further my experience using machine learning and data to create adaptive technology, particularly in the fields of education, healthcare, and scientific research.

#### EXPERIENCE

# Geknowm: Mapping human knowledge

Sept 2012 - Jan 2014

Developed a complete web application (http://geknowm.com) using Ruby on Rails and JavaScript with Backbone.js for organizing educational content, authoring and taking quizzes, and displaying a personal knowledge profile. Designed novel assessment interactions, knowledge extraction algorithms, scoring mechanisms, and data visualizations.

# Learnstream: Web-based learning platform

2009 - 2011

Client: Harvey Mudd College

Designed and developed innovative web-based learning platforms to enhance studying for students using video and spaced repetition practice. The software (http://rudinium.herokuapp.com) was piloted for a mathematics course with over 60 students at Harvey Mudd College. Led a team in developing a second version for physics and calculus content (http://learnstream.heroku.com).

# Cooperative Search with Autonomous Vehicles in a 3D Aquatic Testbed 2010 – 2011 Client: DYNAR (Dynamic Navigation for Aquatic Robots)

Project manager for a team of math and engineering students to develop an aquatic testbed and design and deploy control systems and cooperative behavior algorithms for robotic submarines. Presented work at the Joint Math Meetings in January 2011.

# Resource Allocation for Cloud Computing

**Summer 2010** 

Microsoft Research Asia (UCLA Research in Industrial Projects for Students program)
Investigated modern research on cloud computing. Designed and simulated resource management systems for cloud computing.

#### EDUCATION

#### Carnegie Mellon University

PhD program (one year), Human-Computer Interaction Institute

2011 - 2012

- NSF Graduate Research Fellowship recipient
- Program in Interdisciplinary Education Research (PIER) fellow

# Harvey Mudd College

B.S., Joint Mathematics and Computer Science major

2007 - 2011

- GPA: 3.73/4.0 (magna cum laude)
- Math, computer science, and humanities departmental honors

# SKILLS

# Programming

Ruby, Python, Java, C, C++, C#, Scheme, Haskell, MATLAB

## Web development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery/Backbone.js, Rails, Django

#### Machine learning

Weka, educational data mining

## Mathematics

Problem solving (top 500 Putnam), modeling (MCM Meritorious), tutoring, content writing